longisland.com 2019-05-19

# LongIsland.com Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy Updated: 5/20/2018**

Long Island Media Inc. ("LIM") offers our visitors a secure and private experience while keeping our site, specifically, "LongIsland.com", simple and convenient to use. To do this, in some cases we collect, store and/or use "Personally Identifiable Information", including your name, email address, physical address, telephone number and/or other information that could potentially identify you specifically, subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy. Please note this Privacy Policy is applicable only to information collected by LIM through the site LongIsland.com and does not impact information collected or used by LIM or its Affiliates through other means.

How you interact with the website determines if and when certain information is collected. For instance, some sections or areas of the site allow you to submit contact forms, provide feedback, request information, or signup for newsletters and other services. However, the majority of pages on the site serve visitors purely as "informational" and "read-only" not requiring you to submit anything. However, if and when you choose to participate in certain services by inputting your information, this site will collect this information while other sections may do so automatically by storing 'cookies' and/or placing them in your computers' browser. Among other things, cookies prevent you from having to type the same information each and every time you visit, with the sole purpose of providing an easier user experience. Cookies may also control or limit the amount or the type of advertisements you see while visiting the site. This is intended to provide users a better user experience. 

We also collect information for statistical, website administration and analytical purposes including information regarding your geographic location, your computer or devices IP address, what type of device is being used to visit the site, which websites brought you to the service (web referrals or links from other sites) or even, where applicable, what key phrases on search engines may have led to your visit. We do this only where we are permitted by law to collect and process this information.

As we adopt additional technology, we may also gather information through other means. In certain cases, you can choose not to provide us with any information, for example by setting your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but doing so may limit your ability to access certain portions of the site or may require you to re-enter your user name and password each visit. Additionally we may not be able to customize the site's features according to your preferences. 

For more information on how to clear or prevent cookies from being stored in your browser, [please click here if you are using Firefox](https://support.mozilla.org/en-US/kb/enable-and-disable-cookies-website-preferences), [here for Chrome](https://support.google.com/accounts/answer/61416), and [here for Internet Explorer](https://support.microsoft.com/en-us/help/17442/windows-internet-explorer-delete-manage-cookies).

**How We Use Data Collected.**

First and foremost, we will use your information only as permitted by law and as set forth in this policy. Information that does not personally identify you or any other person specifically may be used in many ways. As one example, we may combine information about your usage patterns with similar information obtained from other users to learn which pages are visited most or what features are most popular. This type of general, non-personal information may occasionally be shared with our advertisers and business partners, but it cannot be used to contact you or any other person individually.

We also collect information to enhance your visit and deliver more individualized content and advertising. For example, we may use Personally Identifiable Information collected on the site to communicate with you regarding other products and services offered by LIM and other LIM Affiliates. We reserve the right to share information with other LIM business units and any entities that control, are controlled by, or are under common control with, LIM (collectively, "Affiliates"), including without limitation LIM's and its Affiliate newspapers, related businesses and websites.

Personally Identifiable Information collected by LIM may also be used for other purposes including but not limited to site administration and troubleshooting. Certain third parties who provide technical support for the operation of our site (our Web hosting service, our newsletter provider, our ISP for example) may also have access to such information. We also contract with other companies to provide services on our behalf, including credit-card and billing processing for our customers and advertisers, ad networks, printing companies, distributors, email servers, list processing and analytics or management. We provide these companies only with the information they need to perform their services.

As we continue to develop our business, we may sell, buy, merge or partner with other companies or businesses, or sell some or all of our assets to other companies or businesses. In such transactions, user information may be among the transferred assets. We may also preserve or disclose your information if required to do so by law, or in good faith belief that such disclosure is reasonably necessary for the following purposes: (1) to comply with legal process, such as a court order, search warrant, or subpoena; (2) to enforce the Terms of Service for this site; (3) to render service you request; (4) to protect the rights or property of LIM, and its third party suppliers and licensors; (5) in circumstances that we deem, in our sole discretion, to pose a threat to the safety of you or others; (6) to protect our rights; or (7) to collect on amounts you may owe us.

**Your Opt Out Options.**

The information on the site is supported by advertising revenue and e-mail newsletters. Like other Web publishers, we sometimes share your information with our advertising and promotional partners to contact, often, but not always, by email, about other services, features, products, or special offers including unique services we believe might interest you. For instance, our weekly newsletters may contain certain advertisements or suggestions, some of which are based on advertising agreements we make with our customers. If you prefer not to receive any communications sent either directly from us, or on behalf of us by a third party, you should not sign up for newsletters, however, if and when you do, you will always be given an opportunity to opt-out.

**Affiliated Sites, Links and Advertisements.**

LIM expects its partners, advertisers and third-party Affiliates to respect the privacy of our users. However, third parties, including our partners, advertisers, Affiliates and other content providers accessible through our site, including social networking sites, may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. For example, during your visit to our site you may link to, or view as part of programmatically inserted content, certain information or advertisements that are actually created or hosted by a third party, such as related news suggestions, or Facebook comments. Also, through the site you may be introduced to, or be able to access, information, Web sites, advertisements, features, contests or sweepstakes offered by other parties. LIM is not responsible for the actions or policies of such third parties. You should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing information on a feature or page which is actually operated by a third party. You should pay special attention and check closely for any labeling or branding next to or aside certain content or functions to help identify the third party.

Additionally, while on our site, our advertisers, promotional partners or other third parties may use cookies or other technology to attempt to identify some of your preferences or retrieve information about you. For example, some of our advertising is served by third parties and may include cookies that enable the advertiser to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before, or that you have visited a particular webpage and may be interested in viewing a particular type of ad. LIM does not control the use of this technology or the resulting information and is not responsible for any actions or policies of such third parties. For more information tracking cookies, [please click here](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0042-online-tracking).

When this happens, a cookie (a tiny file) gets stored by your browser into the "Cookies" folder on your hard drive and may be used by your browser on subsequent visits to the site. When these activities are done to enhance your experience on our site, the data that is collected is the property of LIM. We also allow third parties called ad networks or ad servers to serve ads to you on the site. Cookies enable them to compile information about where you, or others who have used your computer, saw their ads and determine which ads are clicked on both on our site and other sites. This information makes it possible for the ad technology, ad servers and ad networks to deliver targeted advertisements to you on the site and on other sites as you use the web. LIM does not have access to the cookies that may be placed on your computer by third-party ad technology, ad servers or ad networks. LIM maintains relationships with a number of third-party networks. Those parties that use cookies may offer you a way to opt out of ad targeting.

If you would like to opt-out of interest-based or online behavioral advertising, [please click here](http://optout.networkadvertising.org/?c=1#!/).

**Security of Personal Information**

We have implemented commercially reasonable physical and electronic security measures to protect against the loss, misuse, and alteration of your personal information. For instance, but not limited to, we have adopted SSL (Secure Socket Layer) browser technology to protect you when you visit this site (the connection between your browser and the site is encrypted). Despite our best efforts, however, no security measures are impenetrable. To help us protect your privacy, you should maintain the secrecy of your email and the password you may have set up in connection with your participation in this site.

**Children.**

LIM does not knowingly collect or solicit Personally Identifiable Information from or about children under 13 except as permitted by law. If we discover we have received any information from a child under 13 in violation of this policy, we will delete that information immediately. If you believe LIM has any information from or about anyone under 13, please contact us at the address listed below.

**California Privacy Rights.**

Beginning January 1, 2005, California law permits visitors who are California residents to request certain information regarding our disclosure of Personally Identifiable Information to third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make such a request, please send an email or write to us at the contact information below.

**Contacting us.**

Long Island Media Inc.  
67 Harned Road, Suite 3C  
Commack, NY 11725 

Phone: 631-406-4410  
support@longisland.com 

**Changes to Policy.**

LIM reserves the right to change this policy at any time. If you are concerned with your privacy on this site please check this page periodically for changes. Your use of our site means you accept this policy including any changes we make to it, so please check it from time to time. The date of each update to this policy will be posted prominently at the top of this policy.

**Consent for Data Processing Where Applicable.**

Beginning March 25, 2018, some countries outside of the United States will require explicit consent to process and/or use data gathered on certain sites. However, this site is controlled, operated and administered entirely within the United States. It offers its service only in the English language and does not target users in any other counties. If you are located outside the United States, please be aware that while visiting this site information you provide to us through the site may be processed and transferred to the U.S. The privacy and data protection laws in the U.S. may not be equivalent to such laws in your country of residence. By using the Services, you consent to this collection, transfer, storage, and processing of information to and in the U.S.

© 2018 Long Island Media Inc.
